Inventory of the Tower of Peace radio broadcasts
Hoover Institution Archives
Tower of Peace radio broadcasts
1957
57031
Hoover Institution Archives
13 sound tape reels (1.3 linear feet)
Relates to the facilities, history, purpose, and activities of the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Includes interviews with Herbert Hoover and with staff members and researchers at the Hoover Institution. Digital copies also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org
Tower of peace (Radio program).
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of all sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access; digital copies also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1957.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the library catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org
Historical Note
Radio program sponsored by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace.
Scope and Content of Collection
Relates to the facilities, history, purpose, and activities of the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace. Includes interviews with Herbert Hoover and with staff members and researchers at the Hoover Institution.
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace.; Audiotapes.
- Kaltenborn interviews Herbert Hoover about the Hoover Institution, 1957 May 24 (Tape cabinet)
  Access
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008115.
  Scope and Contents note
  Herbert Hoover details the beginnings of the Hoover Institution. The conversation focuses on the logistics of how he delegated collecting duties to others and coordinated the effort into a library at Stanford University.
- Program 1, 1957 March 13 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008116.
  A host interviews Jan Triska and Robert Slusser about their work at the Hoover Institution on the behavior of the Soviet Union, especially as it applies to its relationship with other communist states.
- Program 2, 1957 March 20 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008117.
  A host interviews Ruth Perry, the curator of African collections for the Hoover Institution, and a visiting, African economics student about the African collections at the Hoover Institution.
- Program 3, 1957 March 27 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008120.
  A host interviews Eugene Wu, assistant curator of Asian collections at the Hoover Institution, and Mr. Chiu (sp?) of Stanford University about the Asian collections at the Hoover Institution.
- Program 4, 1957 April 3 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008121.
  A host interviews an assistant director of the Hoover Institution about the Institution's Russian collections, especially as it applies to slave labor.
- Program 5, 1957 April 10 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008122.
  This program concerns Japan, the United States' strategic interests, and the relevant work at the Hoover Institution.
- Program 6, 1957 April 24 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008123.
  A host interviews C. Easton Rothwell, director of the Hoover Institution, and Thomas Thaucan (sp?), the archivist for the Hoover Institution. The program concerns the Hoover Library and Archives, especially Herbert Hoover's personal papers and archives of food relief programs.
- Program 7, 1957 May 1 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008126.
  The host interviews a Jordanian graduate student and a Turkish graduate student about the situation, history, and future of Turkey and the Middle East.
- Program 8, 1957 May 8 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008127.
  This program focuses on the Russian revolutions of 1917. The guest is Robert P. Browder, professor of history at the University of Colorado.
- Program 9, 1957 May 15 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008128.
  This program concerns China, including both Communist and Nationalist China and the Hoover Institution's collections on both. The guests are Mary Wright, curator of the Chinese collection, and Claude Buss, professor of history at Stanford University.
- Program 10, 1957 May 22 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008129.
  This program is about underground movements throughout Europe and the relevant collections of the Hoover Institution. The guests are Agnes Peterson, area associate for Central and Western European collections, and Vernor Varnbrum, foreign student adviser at Stanford University.
- Program 11, 1957 May 29 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008130.
  This program concerns the Arab world and the relevant collections at the Hoover Institution. The guests are professor Christina Harris, curator of Middle Eastern collections, and Graham H. Stuart, former professor of political science and director of the Hoover Library.
- Program 12, 1957 May 29 (Tape cabinet)
  Use copy reference number: 57031_a_0008133.
  This program is about foreign visitors to the Hoover Institution and Library. The guests are Mrs. Inez Richardson, coordinator for foreign visitors to Stanford University, and Hildagard Behringer, program officer in Stanford's office for foreign visitors.